gmacmortgage.com 2009-05-06

# 

**Overview  
** You take your privacy seriously and so does GMAC Mortgage. We are a company committed to protecting the personal information and privacy of our customers. This statement is one way of sustaining your trust in our company, our products and our services.

**Privacy (Website Visitors)**  
Our Online Privacy Statement describes how we collect, protect and use information about you either during your visit to our web site or when you are a GMAC Mortgage customer.

**Information We Collect About You during Your Online Visit**

**_Website Visitors / Registered Users_**  
When you browse our site as a visitor or are a registered user of this website, we may collect and store information about your online visit (see cookies). This information may include the time and length of your visit, the pages you view on our site, the last site you visited before coming to ours, and the name of your internet service provider.

We use this data on an aggregate basis to measure site activity, and on an individual basis to make the site more useful and provide information that may be of interest to you.

**_Registered Users Only_**  
Information collected about registered users is used and shared in accordance with our customer privacy notice and practices. If you are an existing customer, please see the Information Collection and Sharing Practices for Existing Customer section for more information.

As a registered user, you may use the website to:

  * Provide information to us about you when you complete an online application or other form; 
  * Provide information to us about you during web page registration; and 
  * Provide information to us about you during personal profile updates.

**Security Statement**  
 **About our Website(s)**

**Cookies**  
We may use Web cookies for security purposes to recognize your computer when you log into your account. We may also make use of Web cookies or similar data on certain parts of our Web site for fraud prevention and other purposes. If you disable your Web browser's ability to accept our Web cookies, it may not be possible for you to access your online account.

**Passwords**  
Your access to certain portions of our Web site may be protected with an individualized username and password. Your username and password are confidential and personal to you, and should never be disclosed or shared with anyone else.

**Timed logout**  
Certain portions of our Web site may be protected with a timed-logout feature. This can help protect your account from being viewed or used by others if your computer becomes unattended.

**Encryption**  
We may use encryption to protect your information as it travels across the Internet. This can help prevent others from eavesdropping on your browser sessions with our Web servers.

**Firewalls**  
Our Web site may be protected with firewall technology, which can help prevent your account information and our Web site from being improperly accessed.

**Surveillance**  
Certain portions of our Web site are monitored by advanced surveillance and logging technologies. These technologies can help to ensure that both your information and our Web servers are protected from compromise.

**Information Collection and Sharing Practices for Existing Customers**  
 **Existing Customer/Registered Users**

If you are a GMAC Mortgage customer details about the information we collect and how it may be disclosed is contained in our Privacy Notice, which includes additional information regarding your privacy choices. Briefly, we collect information about you for example, when you:

  * Apply for a loan; 
  * Make your monthly payment.

We also collect personal information from you or others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, employers, or others.

**Information We Share About Our Existing Customers**  
The information contained in this section applies to GMAC Mortgage customers.

We may collect and subsequently share personal information about you to:

  * run our everyday business; 
  * respond quickly to customer needs;
  * help us communicate with you
  * evaluate eligibility for additional products and services that may be of interest to you.

**_What We Share_**  
We may share personal information that includes, but is not limited to your:

  * name, address, and other account application information;
  * account balances, transactions, and payment history
  * creditworthiness including credit history and credit score.

**_With Whom We Share_**  
We disclose some of the information we collect about you to third parties such as credit reporting agencies, regulators and loan investors. These types of third parties are called **non-affiliated third parties**.

We may also share some of this information with companies performing services on our behalf such as the vendor who prepares and mails our monthly statements. These types of vendors are called **service providers**.

We may share information we collect about you with companies with whom we have formal agreements to offer you financial products and services. These types of relationships are called **joint marketing** partnerships.

Finally, we may share information we collect about you with companies related by common control (i.e. GMAC Financial Services, GMAC Insurance, Ditech, etc.) to offer you products and services that may be of interest to you. These types of companies are called affiliates.

**_Benefits of sharing_**  
We need to collect and share information about our customers to help us communicate with you.

We also may share customer and former customer information within our GMAC family and with **valued partners** (our employees) to evaluate eligibility, offer and recommend valuable products and services that may be right for you.

**Customer Information Sharing Choices/Opt Out**

**_Federal Law_**  
Federal law requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect personal information about our customers. While Federal law allows us to share information about you to run our business, to perform services and offer our products, Federal law also gives you the right to limit some, but not all, sharing of your personal information.

Specifically, Federal law allows you to opt out/restrict us from sharing information as follows:

  * About your credit worthiness with our affiliates; and
  * To non-affiliates to offer you their products and services
  * creditworthiness including credit history and credit score.

**_State Laws_**  
State laws may give you additional rights regarding our information sharing limitations.

We share personal information about you as permitted by the law of the state in which you reside and in accordance with federal law. As a customer of GMAC Mortgage you received our Privacy Notice when you became our customer and you will receive our updated annual Privacy Notice each year you continue to be our customer.

You can limit us from sharing your information as permitted by law and as described in our Privacy Policy at any time by advising us of your Opt Out choices and how you do not want your information shared by calling **1-877-450-4622**. You may notify us of your choices at any time

If your past choices have not changed, you only need to tell us one time, as long as you have your account with us.

**_Customer Data Protection_**  
We are a company committed to securing personal information and protecting the privacy of our customers. We use security measures that comply with federal law including assessing risk and using reasonable controls to protect customer information.

Our company culture is to treat customer information the way we would want our own information treated. We train employees on handling and securing customer data to maintain a culture of protection and security. It is the responsibility of every associate, affiliate, and nonaffiliate to care for personal information about our customers.

**_Correcting Information_**  
We are committed to maintaining accurate and up-to-date information on all of our customers. We may provide customers with access to account information in different ways, for example, over the telephone, online or on paper.

If you are a registered user of this website, you may be able to update some information online. You will need to log-into your account in order to utilize this feature.

How to contact us regarding your account:

U.S. Mail:  
GMAC Mortgage  
Attn: Customer Service  
P.O. Box 4622  
Waterloo, IA 50704-4622  

Phone: 1-800-766-4622  

Questions about this Online Privacy Statement may be sent via email to: [PrivacyOffice@gmacm.com](mailto:PrivacyOffice@gmacm.com)

**_Policy Effective Date_**  
This Online Privacy Statement is effective February 25th, 2008 and remains in effect until amended. GMAC Mortgage reserves the right to amend this Privacy Statement or alter its privacy principles at its sole discretion without notice to you. We will post any alterations to this Privacy Statement on our web site in a timely manner so please check periodically.

**Identity Theft / Fraudulent Activities**  
 **Identity Theft/Fraud**

Identity Theft occurs when someone uses sensitive information, called Personally Identifiable Information (or PII) of another person without their permission to commit fraud or other crimes, such as Account Takeover or Application Fraud. [ _Account Takeover has occurred when an individual acquires another person's existing credit account information and purchases products and services at the victim's expense. Application Fraud has occurred when an individual uses another's Social Security Number or other Personally Identifiable Information to open new credit accounts in the victim's name._ ]

If you believe you are a victim of Identity Theft, contact the three major credit bureaus to place a fraud alert message on your credit file. When you place a fraud alert on your file, the credit reporting agencies will send you a copy of your credit report at no charge.

  * Experian (1-888-397-3742)
  * Equifax (1-800-525-6285)
  * TransUnion (1-800-680-7289)

Carefully review your credit reports for: accounts you did not open, inquiries from creditors you did not initiate, and for personal information (such as home address and social security number) that is not accurate. If you see anything you do not understand or any accounts you did not open, call the credit reporting agency at the telephone number on the report.

If you decide not to place a fraud alert on your credit file, you can still obtain free copies of your credit report by going to the following Annual Credit Report website ([www.annualcreditreport.com](http://www.annualcreditreport.com/)) or by calling them toll-free at 1-877-322-8228. (Hearing impaired consumers can access their TDD service at 1-877-730-4204.

To learn more about identity theft, visit the Federal Trade Commission's web site to receive further information and insights about how to protect your identity from identity thieves.

Identity Theft Hotline: 877-438-4338  
Web: www.consumer.gov/idtheft  
Mail: Identity Theft Clearinghouse,  
Federal Trade Commission  
600 Pennsylvania Ave., N.W., Washington, DC 20580

There are services that assist in protecting consumers against identity theft. GMAC Mortgage offers its customers Identity Guard® from Intersections, Inc. If you are interested in enrolling in Identity Guard®, please call 866-893-3785 and a representative will assist you. Identity Guard® will be billed to your GMAC Mortgage monthly account statement, so have your mortgage account number available when you call.

**Social Security Number**   
**Privacy Protection Policy**

GMAC Financial Services* collects social security numbers as necessary to support state and federal legal requirements, to provide products or services to you, and to meet our human resources needs. We restrict access to social security numbers to employees, agents, and subcontractors who need social security numbers to support these purposes. We provide social security numbers to government agencies, as required by law. We strive to protect social security numbers from unlawful disclosure and keep them confidential by maintaining physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with applicable state and federal regulations.

***This policy applies to the following GMAC Financial Services companies:** Alexium Leasing Company, American Suzuki Financial Services Company LLC (ASFS), Central Originating Lease Trust (C.O.L. Trust), CIM Insurance Corporation, Ditech, LLC, GHS Mortgage, LLC, GMAC, GMAC Bank, GMAC CF LLC, GMAC Demand Notes, GMAC Direct Insurance Company, GMAC Home Services, LLC, GMAC Insurance Company Online, Inc., GMAC Insurance Management Corporation, GMAC Insurance Marketing, Inc., GMAC Mortgage, LLC, GMAC Mortgage, LLC of TN, GMAC Mortgage USA Corporation, GM Motor Club, Inc., Homecomings Financial, LLC, Homestate County Mutual Insurance Company - Administered by Integon National Insurance Company, Integon Casualty Insurance Company, Integon General Insurance Corporation, Integon Indemnity Corporation, Integon National Insurance Company, Integon Preferred Insurance Company, Integon Specialty Insurance Company, MEEMIC Insurance Company, MEEMIC Insurance Services Corporation, MIC General Insurance Corporation, National Auto Finance Company, National General Assurance Company, National General Insurance Company, New South Insurance Company, Nuvell Credit Company LLC, Nuvell Financial Services LLC, Residential Funding Company, LLC Saab Financial Services LLC, Saab Leasing Company, Semperian, and Union Trust Mortgage Services, Inc.
